Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我叫Catherine。
And today, I think we're hitting the gym, Marco.
今天，我想我们要去健身房了，Marco。
We need to be healthy.
我们需要保持健康。
We've gained weight over the winter, I think.
我想我们冬天长胖了。
I think so.
我也这么觉得。
And being in an office, you know, it doesn't give you much opportunity to go and exercise
而且待在办公室里，你知道，没什么机会去运动，
and really get a lot of work done during the day.
白天真的很难完成很多锻炼。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's why we're going to the gym on this occasion.
所以这就是为什么这次我们要去健身房。
We're going to be pumping some iron.
我们要举铁了。
We're going to be working out.
我们要锻炼了。
So why don't we take a look at Vocabulary Preview and see what this means.
那我们来看看词汇预览，了解一下这是什么意思。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So, to pump iron, what does that mean?
那么，“pump iron”是什么意思？
All right.
好的。
Well, to pumping iron means lifting weights.
嗯，“pump iron”就是举重。
Okay.
好的。
So we're pumping iron.
所以我们在举铁。
We're lifting weights.
我们在举重。
Because, you know, weights are made of iron.
因为，你知道，杠铃是铁做的。
Right.
对。
That's what makes them so heavy.
这就是它们这么重的原因。
All right.
好的。
So we're pumping iron.
所以我们在举铁。
Good.
好。
And, well, we're going to be giving you guys some pointers.
而且，我们会给你们一些建议。
Pointers.
建议。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So you might have heard the word point before.
你可能以前听过“point”这个词。
And pointers is another word for tips.
“Pointers”是“tips”的另一种说法。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to be giving you tips or advice.
所以我们会给你们一些提示或建议。
Yeah.
是的。
So you're going to get some help today from the trainer.
所以今天你会从教练那里得到一些帮助。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to jump right into this dialogue.
那我们直接进入对话吧。
And when we come back, we'll be talking more about what's going on.
等我们回来，我们会再聊聊发生了什么。
Hey there.
嘿，你好。
You look a little lost.
你看起来有点迷茫。
Are you new here?
你是新来的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
How did you know?
你怎么知道的？
You can always spot the newbies.
你总能认出新手。
I can give you a few pointers if you want.
如果你愿意，我可以给你一些建议。
Were you trying to use this machine here?
你刚才想用这台机器吗？
Yeah.
是的。
I just started my training today, and I'm not sure where to begin.
我今天刚开始训练，不知道从哪里开始。
It's okay.
没关系。
I know how it is.
我懂这种感觉。
This machine here will work out your upper body, mainly your triceps and biceps.
这台机器可以锻炼你的上半身，主要是肱三头肌和肱二头肌。
Are you looking to develop strength or muscle tone and definition?
你是想增强力量，还是想练肌肉线条和清晰度？
Well, I don't want to be ripped like you.
嗯，我不想练得像你那样肌肉发达。
I just want a good physique with weights and cardio.
我只想通过举重和有氧运动练出好身材。
In that case, you want to work with less weight.
那样的话，你应该用轻一点的重量。
You can start off by working 10 to 15 reps in four sets.
你可以从每组10到15次，做四组开始。
Five kilo weights should be enough.
五公斤的重量应该够了。
Now it's very important that you stretch before pumping iron.
现在，举铁前拉伸非常重要。
You might pull a muscle.
你可能会拉伤肌肉。
Got it.
明白了。
Wow.
哇。
Is that the weight you're lifting?
那是你举的重量吗？
My goodness, that's a lot of weight.
天哪，那可真重。
It's not that much.
没那么重。
Just watch.
看着吧。
I'm okay.
我没事。
So this guy was a little bit arrogant.
所以这家伙有点自大。
I think he was very muscular, but I think he embarrassed himself in front of the lady.
我觉得他肌肉很发达，但他在那位女士面前出丑了。
The trainer, you mean?
你是说教练？
Yeah.
是的。
Yeah, definitely.
对，绝对是。
So we say he had a big ego.
所以我们说他自尊心很强。
He thought a lot about himself.
他太自以为是了。
So let's check out some of these phrases and words that they were using because they're
那我们来看看他们用的一些短语和单词，因为
all related to going to the gym, and they can help you if you ever want to get some
这些都和去健身房有关，如果你在健身房需要帮助，
help when you're at the gym.
它们能派上用场。
So this girl, she was new in the gym.
所以这个女孩是健身房的新手。
She didn't really know what she was doing.
她不太清楚自己在做什么。
And well, the guy said, well, do you want to develop strength or muscle tone?
然后那个男的说，你想增强力量还是练肌肉线条？
All right.
好的。
We know what strength is, but what is muscle tone?
我们知道力量是什么，但肌肉线条是什么？
Okay.
好的。
So if you want to develop muscle tone or to have muscle tone, it means that you have healthy
如果你想练肌肉线条或有肌肉线条，意思是你的肌肉很健康，
muscles, not like huge, big muscles, right?
不是那种巨大、夸张的肌肉，对吧？
But you have a nice body.
而是身材很好。
Right.
对。
So tone, to tone is to maybe give some shape to something.
所以“tone”，塑形，就是给某物一些形状。
Sometimes you have big arms and you can't see the muscles.
有时候你手臂很粗，但看不到肌肉。
Well, muscle tone means that you can start to see the shape and they start to get stronger.
嗯，肌肉线条意味着你能开始看到形状，肌肉也开始变强壮。
All right.
好的。
So if you think of Madonna, maybe five years ago, she had a lot of muscle tone.
所以如果你想到麦当娜，大概五年前，她肌肉线条很好。
Now she's like big muscles.
现在她肌肉很大块了。
But muscle tone means that you can see the muscles, they start to develop.
但肌肉线条意味着你能看到肌肉，它们开始发展。
Okay.
好的。
And this actually is very related to our next word because you said muscle tone and definition.
这其实和我们下一个词很相关，因为你提到了肌肉线条和清晰度。
Right.
对。
So definition is another way for us to describe seeing those muscles because at first you
所以“definition”是另一种描述看到肌肉的方式，因为一开始
have a big tummy or you have big arms and when you start to work out, every time you
你肚子大或手臂粗，当你开始锻炼，每次去，
go, you can see more and more definition.
你会看到越来越清晰的线条。
That means more and more of the muscle becomes visible.
这意味着越来越多的肌肉变得可见。
All right.
好的。
So you have defined muscles.
所以你有清晰的肌肉。
All right.
好的。
Good.
好。
Now the girl was like, no, no, I don't want to be like super strong and huge.
现在那个女孩说，不，不，我不想变得超级强壮和巨大。
She doesn't want to look like Arnold Schwarzenegger.
她不想看起来像阿诺德·施瓦辛格。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
She said, I just want a good physique.
她说，我只想要好身材。
All right.
好的。
So this word maybe sounds strange for some of you because it's more like French than
这个词对你们有些人来说可能听起来有点奇怪，因为它更像法语
English.
而不是英语。
Yeah.
是的。
Well, it does come from French and physique is a way to talk about the whole body.
嗯，它确实来自法语，“physique”是描述整个身体的一种方式。
You know, the physique is the state of your whole body.
你知道，身材就是你整个身体的状态。
It's your physical appearance.
就是你的外貌。
Okay.
好的。
So I can say she has a nice physique.
所以我可以说她身材很好。
So that means she's probably works out a lot.
那意味着她可能经常锻炼。
So but basically it's like her whole body, right?
但基本上就是她的整个身体，对吧？
You can't just say like she has good physique in her arms or something like that.
你不能只说她的手臂身材好之类的。
And now your physique, physical, think of the word physical.
现在你的“physique”，身体的，想想“physical”这个词。
It's your whole body, your whole body.
是你的整个身体，整个身体。
All right.
好的。
So good physique.
所以好身材。
And now the tips that he was giving her or the pointers, he was talking about these two
现在他给她的建议或提示，他提到了这两个词：
words reps and sets.
“reps”和“sets”。
Right.
对。
These are great words for the gym because they, they allow us to count when we're working
这些是健身房里的好词，因为它们让我们在锻炼时
out.
能计数。
So the first one is reps or repetitions.
第一个是“reps”或“repetitions”。
That means doing something over and over again.
意思是反复做某事。
So for example, if I want to lift a weight, I sit down on the bench, I do one, two, three.
比如，如果我想举重，我坐在长凳上，做一、二、三。
How many times I lift that weight is a repetition or a rep.
我举多少次就是一次重复或一次“rep”。
All right.
好的。
And well, and what about sets?
那“sets”呢？
So I could say I lift the weight 10 times, one, two, three, four, all the way to 10.
所以我可以说我举重10次，一、二、三、四，一直到10。
And then I wait and then I do it again.
然后我休息，然后再做一次。
So the number of times I do it again is a set.
所以再做一次的次数就是一组。
So sets of 10 or sets of five.
所以是10次一组或5次一组。
Okay.
好的。
So if you are lifting this weight 10 times and you have five sets, you will do a total
所以如果你举重10次，做五组，你总共会做
of 50 pushes or lifts or repetitions.
50次推举或举重或重复。
Okay.
好的。
So reps and sets are probably the most important or common words you'll hear in the gym, especially
所以“reps”和“sets”可能是你在健身房听到的最重要或最常见的词，尤其是
if you're lifting weights.
如果你举重的话。
Right.
对。
Definitely.
绝对是。
And sometimes your trainer will count with you so that he'll, he'll keep a count while
有时候你的教练会和你一起数，这样他会在你锻炼时
you're working out.
保持计数。
Cool.
酷。
So those are the words that we have for you on Language Takeaway.
这些就是我们在语言要点部分为你准备的单词。
I think in order to better understand these words, we should listen to our dialogue again,
我觉得为了更好地理解这些词，我们应该再听一遍对话，
but we're going to slow it down just a little bit.
但我们会稍微放慢速度。
Hey there.
嘿，你好。
You look a little lost.
你看起来有点迷茫。
Are you new here?
你是新来的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
How did you know?
你怎么知道的？
You can always spot the newbies.
你总能认出新手。
I can give you a few pointers if you want.
如果你愿意，我可以给你一些建议。
Were you trying to use this machine here?
你刚才想用这台机器吗？
Yeah.
是的。
I just started my training today.
我今天刚开始训练。
I'm not really sure where to begin.
我不太确定从哪里开始。
It's okay.
没关系。
I know how it is.
我懂这种感觉。
This machine here will work out your upper body, mainly your triceps and biceps.
这台机器可以锻炼你的上半身，主要是肱三头肌和肱二头肌。
Are you looking to develop strength or muscle tone and definition?
你是想增强力量，还是想练肌肉线条和清晰度？
Well, I don't want to be ripped like you.
嗯，我不想练得像你那样肌肉发达。
I just want a good physique with weights and cardio.
我只想通过举重和有氧运动练出好身材。
In that case, you want to work with less weight.
那样的话，你应该用轻一点的重量。
You can start off by working 10 to 15 reps in four sets.
你可以从每组10到15次，做四组开始。
Five kilo weights should be enough.
五公斤的重量应该够了。
Now, it's very important that you stretch before pumping iron or you might pull a muscle.
现在，举铁前拉伸非常重要，否则你可能会拉伤肌肉。
Got it.
明白了。
Wow.
哇。
Is that the weight you're lifting?
那是你举的重量吗？
My goodness, that's a lot of weight.
天哪，那可真重。
It's not that much.
没那么重。
Just watch.
看着吧。
I'm okay.
我没事。
All right.
好的。
So, you might have heard some other phrases in there that sound interesting or new to
所以，你可能在对话中听到了一些听起来有趣或陌生的
you.
短语。
That's why we're going to go into the fluency builder part of the lesson where we can talk
这就是为什么我们要进入课程的流利度提升部分，在那里我们可以讨论
about sounding more fluent in English.
如何让英语听起来更流利。
Fluency builder.
流利度提升。
All right.
好的。
So, the girl, she was a little bit lost, right?
所以，那个女孩有点迷茫，对吧？
So, this guy was trying to help her out.
所以这个男的在帮她。
I think it was her first time in the gym.
我想这是她第一次去健身房。
It was.
是的。
She doesn't really know where to start, which is a common problem for people who go to the
她不太知道从哪里开始，这是第一次去健身房的人
gym for the first time.
常见的问题。
So, the guy said, well, yeah, I know how it is.
所以那个男的说，嗯，是的，我懂这种感觉。
How what is?
懂什么感觉？
Exactly.
没错。
How what is?
怎么是什么？
It's a very strange phrase because it's vague.
这是一个很奇怪的短语，因为它很模糊。
It's not clear.
它不明确。
So, what is he referring to?
那么，他指的是什么呢？
This is something very common that we say in English to mean, I understand your situation.
这是我们在英语中常说的一句话，意思是“我理解你的处境”。
I know how you feel.
我懂你的感受。
So, she says, this is my first time.
所以，她说，这是我第一次。
I don't know what to do.
我不知道该怎么办。
And he says, I know how it is.
然后他说，我懂这种感觉。
I understand your situation.
我理解你的处境。
Right, because I imagine the first time he went to the gym, he felt the same way.
对，因为我想他第一次去健身房时也有同样的感觉。
Exactly.
没错。
Or I could say, I'm so lost.
或者我可以说，我完全迷茫了。
I'm new at this school.
我是这所学校的新生。
I don't even know anyone.
我甚至一个人都不认识。
Yeah, I know how it is.
是啊，我懂这种感觉。
I was new here last year.
我去年也是新来的。
So, trust me, I know how it is.
所以，相信我，我懂这种感觉。
Okay.
好的。
So, Marco and I have similar situations, although he has already experienced it.
所以，马可和我有相似的处境，尽管他已经经历过了。
So, he can help me out.
所以，他可以帮我。
This is a good phrase.
这是一个好短语。
It's actually, I think it's very common for somebody to kind of sympathize with you.
实际上，我觉得这是别人同情你时很常用的一种说法。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
And it's a really good phrase if you want to help someone who looks lost or confused.
如果你想帮助一个看起来迷茫或困惑的人，这是一个非常好的短语。
So, if someone joins your work, if you have a new colleague, and they say, oh, I don't
所以，如果有人加入你的工作，如果你有一个新同事，他们说，哦，我什么
know where anything is.
东西在哪儿都不知道。
I don't know how to do anything at my job.
我工作上什么都不会做。
You say, oh, I know how it is.
你就说，哦，我懂这种感觉。
I was new here last month.
我上个月也是新来的。
Great.
很好。
And, well, now they were talking about, you know, lifting weights and the physique.
然后，他们现在在谈论，你知道，举重和体型。
And she said this interesting word.
她说了一个有趣的词。
She says, I don't want to be ripped like you.
她说，我不想练得像你那样肌肉发达。
Okay.
好的。
And many of you have probably heard the other meaning of the word to rip or ripped.
你们很多人可能听过“rip”或“ripped”这个词的另一个意思。
So, this is to rip.
所以，这是“撕裂”的意思。
Yeah, to tear.
对，撕开。
But in this case, it's an adjective.
但在这里，它是一个形容词。
It's a way to describe someone's physique, their body.
这是一种描述某人身材、体型的方式。
And we're talking about people who are very, very muscular.
我们说的是那些非常非常肌肉发达的人。
Okay.
好的。
So, basically, bodybuilders.
所以，基本上就是健美运动员。
Arnold Schwarzenegger is ripped.
阿诺德·施瓦辛格肌肉发达。
He has huge muscles.
他有巨大的肌肉。
Madonna is ripped.
麦当娜肌肉发达。
She has huge muscles.
她有巨大的肌肉。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's a very informal way, but it's a very informal way of saying very muscular.
所以，这是一种非常非正式的说法，表示“非常肌肉发达”。
Yeah.
对。
It's someone who works out a lot.
这是指经常锻炼的人。
All right.
好的。
You're ripped.
你肌肉发达。
And after this, we've got one more phrase.
之后，我们还有一个短语。
It's actually very important because when we talk about going to the gym, working out,
实际上它非常重要，因为当我们谈论去健身房、锻炼时，
we have to talk about safety and your health as well.
我们也必须谈论安全和健康。
It's very easy to hurt yourself.
很容易伤到自己。
Right.
对。
And that's what we want to avoid.
这就是我们想要避免的。
You don't want to pull a muscle.
你不想拉伤肌肉。
All right.
好的。
Pull a muscle.
拉伤肌肉。
And this is a key phrase here because we have a special combination of verb and noun.
这是一个关键短语，因为这里有一个特殊的动词和名词组合。
The thing that we pull is our muscle.
我们拉伤的是肌肉。
And what we do to it is we pull it.
我们对它做的就是拉伤它。
That means we hurt it.
意思是弄伤它。
So if you don't stretch and you're lifting weights, maybe your muscle will start to hurt
所以如果你不拉伸就举重，你的肌肉可能会开始疼，
and you can't lift anymore.
你就不能再举了。
Yeah.
对。
You hurt it.
你弄伤了它。
You pulled your muscle.
你拉伤了肌肉。
You pulled a muscle.
Or often runners have this problem.
或者跑步者经常有这个问题。
They don't stretch before they run or they run too much.
他们跑步前不拉伸，或者跑得太多。
And they have a lot of pain in their muscles.
然后他们的肌肉很疼。
You say, I pulled a muscle.
你说，我拉伤了肌肉。
Now, I think there's another way of saying it also is to tear a muscle, right?
现在，我觉得还有一种说法是“撕裂肌肉”，对吧？
Tear is more serious.
“撕裂”更严重。
More serious.
更严重。
A tear is like a little rip in your muscle and you should really see a doctor about that.
撕裂就像肌肉上有个小口子，你真的应该去看医生。
Okay.
好的。
So we don't want you to pull a muscle or to tear a muscle.
所以我们不希望你们拉伤肌肉或撕裂肌肉。
So be sure to stretch.
所以一定要拉伸。
But we have some more examples with this phrase, to pull a muscle.
但我们还有更多关于“拉伤肌肉”这个短语的例子。
So let's listen.
让我们听听。
Example one.
例子一。
Physical strains also called pull muscles are common sports injuries.
肌肉拉伤，也叫肌肉劳损，是常见的运动损伤。
Example two.
例子二。
If you do not warm up before a physical activity, you can easily pull a muscle.
如果你在体育活动前不热身，很容易拉伤肌肉。
Example three.
例子三。
Anyone can pull a muscle because of overuse, muscle fatigue or through a fall.
任何人都有可能因为过度使用、肌肉疲劳或摔倒而拉伤肌肉。
Alright so now that that's clear, I think we can listen to our gym dialer one more time
好了，现在清楚了，我想我们可以再听一遍我们的健身房对话，
and see what happens to this arrogant bodybuilder.
看看这个傲慢的健美运动员会怎么样。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
Hey there.
嘿，你好。
You look a little lost.
你看起来有点迷茫。
Are you new here?
你是新来的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
How did you know?
你怎么知道的？
You can always spot the newbies.
你总能认出新手。
I can give you a few pointers if you want.
如果你愿意，我可以给你一些指点。
Were you trying to use this machine here?
你刚才想用这台机器吗？
Yeah.
是的。
I just started my training today and I'm not sure where to begin.
我今天刚开始训练，不知道从哪里开始。
It's okay.
没关系。
I know how it is.
我懂这种感觉。
This machine here will work out your upper body, mainly your triceps and biceps, and
这台机器可以锻炼你的上半身，主要是肱三头肌和肱二头肌，还有
your glutes.
你的臀部。
So you can do a lot of different exercises.
所以你可以做很多不同的练习。
I'm going to show you how to do a few exercises.
我来教你几个动作。
So I'm going to start with a squat.
我先从深蹲开始。
I'm going to start with a squat.
I like to run and I often use the treadmill.
我喜欢跑步，经常用跑步机。
And I've never really understood the people
我一直不太理解那些
who don't run on the treadmill,
不在跑步机上跑步的人，
people who stand or who walk slowly.
那些站着或慢走的人。
And I remember my gym is usually very crowded.
我记得我的健身房通常很拥挤。
I remember one time I was at my gym
我记得有一次我在健身房，
and I wanted to run on the treadmill.
我想在跑步机上跑步。
I had a long day at work and I had to go out afterwards.
我工作了一天很累，之后还要出去。
So I didn't have much time.
所以我没有太多时间。
I only had an hour and I really wanted to run,
我只有一个小时，真的很想跑步，
but there's a line for the treadmills.
但跑步机前有人在排队。
There are too many people.
人太多了。
And this particular day I was waiting
那天我一直在等
and waiting and waiting.
啊等啊等。
And finally it was my turn and I stepped
终于轮到我了，我正要
and a woman cut in front of me.
上去，一个女人插队到我前面。
No.
不会吧。
She cut in front of me and I was so angry.
她插队到我前面，我气坏了。
And what did she do?
她做了什么？
In her heels.
穿着高跟鞋。
Heels?
高跟鞋？
Heels, big shoes.
高跟鞋，大鞋子。
She walked for 40 minutes.
她走了40分钟。
Oh my God.
哦，我的天。
You could go outside and walk.
你可以出去外面走啊。
I wanna run.
我想跑步。
But she was wearing heels at the gym.
但她在健身房穿着高跟鞋。
In her heels at the gym.
穿着高跟鞋在健身房。
Wow, well, I guess you have to look nice
哇，好吧，我想你去健身房也得
when you go to the gym also.
打扮得好看点。
Apparently, apparently.
显然，显然。
It is a very popular place for people to meet, right?
那是个很受欢迎的交友场所，对吧？
To start dating.
开始约会。
It is.
是的。
They say after the office, the gym is one
他们说除了办公室，健身房是
of the most common places for people
人们最常遇到
to meet their boyfriends and girlfriends.
男朋友或女朋友的地方之一。
Wow, so there's another good reason
哇，所以这是另一个
why you should go to the gym.
你应该去健身房的好理由。
Absolutely, yeah.
绝对是的，对。
All right, so that's all the time we have for today,
好了，今天的时间就到这里，
but we would like to hear if you have any questions,
但我们想听听你们是否有任何问题、
any doubts or comments.
疑问或评论。
So come to our site, EnglishPod.com.
所以来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
And if you have any gym stories,
如果你有任何健身房的故事，
we'd also like to hear those.
我们也想听听。
So that's gonna do it for us.
今天就到这里。
Until next time, everyone, bye.
下次再见，大家，拜拜。
All right, bye.
好的，拜拜。